<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Child on the Cliffs</title>
            <author>By Edward Thomas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>LRBS Digital Editing Exercise</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Source: 1918 Poems</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>The Child on the Cliffs <lb/> By Edward Thomas</head>
            <lg type="sestet">
               <l>Mother, the root of this little yellow flower</l>
               <l>Among the stones has the taste of quinine.</l>
               <l>Things are strange to-day on the cliff. The sun shines so bright,</l>
               <l>And the grasshopper works at his sewing-machine</l>
               <l>So hard. Here’s one on my hand, mother, look;</l>
               <l>I lie so still. There’s one on your book.</l>
            </lg>

            <lg type="sestet">
               <l>But I have something to tell more strange. So leave</l>
               <l>Your book to the grasshopper, mother dear,—</l>
               <l>Like a green knight in a dazzling market-place,—</l>
               <l>And listen now. Can you hear what I hear</l>
               <l>Far out? Now and then the foam there curls</l>
               <l>And stretches a white arm out like a girl’s.</l>
            </lg>

            <lg type="sestet">
               <l>Fishes and gulls ring no bells. There cannot be</l>
               <l>A chapel or church between here and Devon,</l>
               <l>With fishes or gulls ringing its bell,—hark!—</l>
               <l>Somewhere under the sea or up in heaven.</l>
               <l>“It’s the bell, my son, out in the bay</l>
               <l>On the buoy. It does sound sweet to-day.”</l>
            </lg>

            <lg type="sestet">
               <l>Sweeter I never heard, mother, no, not in all Wales.</l>
               <l>I should like to be lying under that foam,</l>
               <l>Dead, but able to hear the sound of the bell,</l>
               <l>And certain that you would often come</l>
               <l>And rest, listening happily.</l>
               <l>I should be happy if that could be.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>


      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
